Yasin Deger

QA Engineer

 \bowtie

yasin.deger48@gmail.com



+905308729244



linkedin.com/in/yasindeger

•

Izmir, Turkey

SUMMARY:

I plan and coordinate the testing activities for Web and API applications, ensuring the highest quality standards and performance metrics. I have over 3+ years of experience in software testing and 5+ years of experience in software development, I have a bachelor's degree in computer science, ISTQB certificate and multiple certifications in test automation tools and frameworks.

I have created a Selenium, Selenide and Playwright frameworks with Java from scratch, implementing test cases to increase test coverage and test efficiency. I have performed dockerize environment for test executions as built in. I have also performed various types of functional and non-functional testing, such as smoke, regression, positive, negative, boundary value analysis, stress, load, and spike testing.

I can use k6 and Jmeter as a performance tool to simulate virtual user scenarios and measure the system's response. I leverage Jenkins, GitHub actions continuous integration, Jira Xray for project management, and GitHub and other platforms of version control and collaboration.

SKILLS:

Programming Languages	Java, JavaScript
CI/CD	Jenkins, Github Actions, TravisCI, Buddy, Device Farm Structures
Testing FRAMEWORK/	Playwright, Selenium, Selenide, Appium (IOS and Android),
Tool	Katalon Studio, TestNG, Junit, Cucumber BDD, Gauge BDD,
	Postman, Maven, Rest Assured, JDBC, Docker, Selenium GRID,
	k6, Jmeter, Apache POI, Custom Reporting with Web Hooks
Databases	Oracle and other relational databases
IDE	IntelliJ, VS Code
Bug Tracking Tool	JIRA X-ray, Trello
Operating System	MacOS X, Windows, Linux

EXPERIENCE:

Trustmeup QA Engineer Team Lead

May 2023 – Present

Summary: I plan and coordinate the testing activities for Web and API applications, ensuring the highest quality standards and performance metrics. This project is a web-based application for the donation. Managing and simulating donor behaviours.

Responsibilities:

- Implementing Test Cases to increase Test coverage and Test efficiency.
- Creating Playwright framework with Java from scratch.
- Performed different type of testing such as Functional and Non-functional.
- Functional part consists of smoke, regression, positive, negative and boundary value analysis.
- Non- functional part consists of stress, load and spike testing with k6 performance tool.
- Implementing Jenkins for Continuous Integration
- Jira Xray is using as project management tool.
- Involving all Agile Scrum ceremonies.
- Using Slack reporting and communication platform

Virgosol

Test Architecture Team Lead

Sep 2022 – May 2023

Summary: I have served in e-commerce CRM and various mobile test projects. After making numerous contributions to the test architecture, I was promoted to lead the test architecture team. Being involved in multiple projects, this has been one of the areas where my domain knowledge has significantly developed.

Responsibilities:

- Katalon Studio Instructor.
- Implemented Test Cases to increase Test coverage and Test efficiency.
- Involved to creation different type of Test Automation Frameworks.
- Performed different Test types such as Smoke, Regression, Positive and Negative Testing.
- Used Jira and Trello as a project management tool.
- Involved different platforms such as Web, Database, API, Mobile, Desktop (Katalon)
- Involved in all Scrum ceremonies.
- Teams, Zoom, Discord, Slack and WhatsApp are used as a communication platform

Fleet Apps QA Engineer

Sep 2021 – Aug 2022

Summary: This project is a web-based application for the fleet management. This application helps fleet management companies to manage all kind of their logistic issues. It is mainly used for renting, tracking, and maintaining fleets, consisting of monitoring fleet activities and costs.

Responsibilities:

- Prepared Test Cases to increase Test coverage and Test efficiency.
- Involved to creation of Cucumber Behavior Driven Development (BDD) Test Automation FRAMEWORK from scratch using Selenium WebDriver, JUnit, Maven, JAVA by utilizing Page Object Model.
- Implemented Gherkin language in Test scenarios.
- Performed different Test types for the implementation of the project such as Regression, Smoke, Positive and Negative Testing.
- Used Git/GitHub as the Version Control System
- Used JIRA X-ray as the Defect Tracking tool.
- Run SQL queries and used JDBC for validating the data in database.
- Involved in all scrum ceremonies (Planning, Daily, Demo, Retro)
- Zoom, Discord and Meet as a communication platform.

Summary: This project is a web-based application for the enterprise resource planning (ERP). This application organizes and manage day by day business activities such as accounting, project management and compliance, and supply chain operations. This project also includes enterprise performance management, software that helps plan, budget, predict, and report on an organization's financial results.

Responsibilities:

- Involved in all scrum ceremonies. (Planning, Daily, Demo, Retro)
- Created Test FRAMEWORK from scratch with JAVA, Selenium, Cucumber, JUnit
- Performed manual Testing, regression, and smoke Testing.
- Created tickets for Test, bug report, and Test executions in JIRA X-ray
- Implemented parallel Testing
- Executed on Jenkins and getting report via email
- Connected Database with JDBC Library and verified with User Interface.
- Zoom and Discord as a communication platform.

Government of Turkey System Software Manager

Aug 2009 - Mar 2020

Summary: I worked as Programmer Officer. During this time, I was dealing with the big data coming from computer systems and stored and managed this data and prepared some documentation related for them. I worked and tested on ship shore ship buffer data-link management system. I took lots of certificate from NATO. At the same time, I managed system personals over hundred. I gained successful experience in terms of personnel and system management. I am experienced in training for the team and how to behave in a stressful work environment.

Responsibilities:

- Involved in daily ceremonies.
- Maintenance system software periodically
- Creating priodically reports and documentation

EDUCATION:

• Tur AF Academy Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

2005 - 2009

• ISTQB Foundation Level

2023